# **FARHAD MOKHTAR**

# General Manager - Operations | Strategic Planning | Performance Management | Operations **Excellence**

📞 +91 9823281182 🏻 @ farhadmokhtar3@gmail.com 🕜 www.linkedin.com/in/farhad-mokhtar-117b4080 , Pune, Maharashtra, India

# **EXPERIENCE**

# General Manager - Operations

#### ContentCAB.IN

ContentCAB. In is prominent source of coupon content creation since 2003. It is at the forefront of online savings boasting of tens of millions loyal shoppers and over 6000 partner stores in North America.

- In charge of the entire site, its infrastructure and day to day operations for 250 FTE
- Leader of leaders, managing all Sr Operations Managers, Operation Managers, HR Head and other HR personnel along with all Agents, Executives, Head Trainers, Trainers and Auxiliary Staff.
- Set up the entire recruitment process and ramped the site from 30 employees to 250 FTE.
- · Spearheaded onboarding, activating and training of all 220+ new hires.
- Policymaker for recruitment, compensations, performance incentives and
- HR policymaker for leave policies, adherence to all labour laws in a 24/7 work environment.
- · Hired for several management positions and trained them for operational roles.
- · Capacity Planning, budgeting, resource allocation for entire site.
- Spearheaded designing and implementing employee performance metrics in alignment with company goals.
- Analyzed data to identify key KPIs, setting up benchmarks for performance metrics and trends.
- · Leveraged performance data and set up a team of high performing managers and implemented site wide training and retraining programmes.
- · Organised and Executed quarterly R&R programmes.
- · Boosted customer satisfaction by 40% by implementing Customer Experience metric and reorganizing support teams.
- Streamlined production efficiency by 25% by integrating volume based staffing and deploying cross-functional teams.

# APAC Capacity planning Leader / Operations Leader (AVP), Customer Service and Moderation Ops

# **Amazon E-Commerce**

**=** 01/2017 - 03/2024

Pune, Maharashtra

Amazon.com is a leading multinational technology company specializing in ecommerce, cloud computing, and AI, operating globally across diverse markets.

- Led operations for Amazon India, overseeing 1000+ employees across 9
- Collaborated with global teams to align ops cost, site, and hiring strategy.
- Spearheaded site launches and set operational metrics, managing headcount
- Launched two new customer service lines in the UAE and Saudi Arabia.
- Pioneered moderation ops for English-speaking markets, enhancing product
- Developed programs reducing hiring by 65 managers, saving \$1.65 million.
- Awarded Leader of the Leaders for five consecutive quarters.
- Won 2019 Diamond Award for exceptional leadership.
- · Led several offsite recreational programmes.
- Conceptualized, executed and managed events for over 5000 employees.
- Led the team R&R Programme consecutively for 4 years.
- Directly responsible for over 1000+ employees and 60 managers.
- · Successfully accomplished retraining and curating a high performing team to manage operations and capacity planning.
- · Competent at designing and streamlining systems and procedures to ensure timely availability of business information for informed decision making.
- · Managed various accounts with domain expertise in e-commerce, customer service, retail and payments.

#### SUMMARY

I am a seasoned Senior Leader with over 21 years of experience in customer service, moderation operations, and program management. My strengths lie in strategic planning, quality assurance, and performance management, complemented by a track record of leading large teams and achieving operational excellence across multiple countries. I have a passion for facilitating organizational growth through effective training and innovative solutions.

#### KEY ACHIEVEMENTS



#### **Key Achievements**

Award recipient of multiple awards across companies.

Diamond Award - Amazon Employee of the Year in 2019

Torch Bearer Award - Amazon Won this award 3 times for 3 consecutive

CARE Leader - Amazon 8 Times in 12 months

Star Leader - WNS Won for 2 consecutive years

Employee of the year - Hutchinson 3 Global

Won this prestigious award twice

#### SKILLS

#### **Stakeholder Management**

**P&L Management** 

**Project Management** 

**Operations Management** 

**Vendor Management** 

**SLA Management** 

Compliance

**Quality Management** 

**Change Management** 

**Customer Experience** 

**Coaching & Mentoring** 

# **LANGUAGES**

# **English**

Native



Hindi

Native



# **EXPERIENCE**

# Deputy Manager - Operations

# WNS Global Services Pvt. Ltd.

WNS Global Services is a leading provider of business processing outsourcing services.

- Customer Service Deputy Manager managing 600+ HC Insurance Process.
- · Heading assessment of client training and implementations.
- Responsible for aligning internal and external stakeholder expectations across teams.
- · Ensured day to day operations, planning, coordination, and administration adhered to Suncorp SOPs and standards.
- Led a cross-functional team of approximately 100 FTEs to achieve financial targets.
- Evaluated, analyzed, and identified opportunities to increase CSAT rates.
- Introduced necessary KPI and MSI reports.
- Implemented weekly and monthly contractual KPI reports for stakeholders.
- · Established and monitored key risk indicators and implemented corrective action plans to mitigate risks.
- Planned and assessed FTE requirements based on volume forecasting using historical data trends.

#### Team Leader - Operations

#### **Hutchinson 3 Global Services**

Hutchinson 3 Global Services is a leading telecom service provider.

- Customer Service Team Leader Telecom UK Process.
- Leading a team in Operations, Training and Development for 45= HC.
- · Accountable for team performance, process SLAs, and quality while leading a team of 20= advisors.
- · Expertly managed functional responsibilities with operations, training, and development to ensure qualitative outputs.
- · Analyzed performance metrics and developed action plans for performance improvement and sustainability.

#### Assistant Manager - Business Development

# **Reltronics Technologies**

**= 11/2006 - 04/2008** 

Pune, Maharashtra

Reltronics Technologies operates in the telecommunications sector focusing on sales and business development.

- Managing a team of 60=HC in Business Development, Sales and Marketing.
- Driving robust lead generation program and consistently meeting team sales taraets.
- Managed customer interface across all levels of communication on weekly, monthly and quarterly basis.
- · Aligned goals with organizational policies.
- Spearheaded interviewing, hiring, training, planning, direct work, appraising performance, rewarding, discipline for all team members.

# Team Leader - Operations

#### **Wipro BPO**

Wipro BPO is a major player in the Business Process Outsourcing industry.

- Leading a team in Operations, Training and Development for 25=HC.
- · Managed a team of agents by monitoring, coaching, and counseling individual performance.
- Generated and managed team rosters.
- · Conducted audits on internal process such as PMS, appraisals, and client calibrations.

# **EDUCATION**

### Bachelor's in Business Administration

#### **Pune University**

苗 08/1999 - 06/2002 👂 Pune, Maharashtra

# **LANGUAGES**

#### Marathi

Beginner



#### STRENGTHS

### Strategic planning excellence

Proven track record in strategic planning and effective implementation.



#### Leadership expertise

Led multiple high-performing teams in diverse